<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: General | Pradeep Sadanapalli]]></title>
  <link href="http://sadanapalli.com/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sadanapalli.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-21T15:16:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://sadanapalli.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pradeep Sadanapalli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Github Pages, Jekyll, Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://sadanapalli.com/2014/03/04/hello-github-pages/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T05:44:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://sadanapalli.com/2014/03/04/hello-github-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My site is hosted on <a href="http://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> and it is powered by <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>/<a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>.</p>




<p>Earlier I have used <a href="http://www.wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and <a href="http://www.blogger.com">Blogger</a> platforms to power my sites/blogs. I am attracted by the prospect of using Octopress/Jekyll/Github due to few factors (which I will explain in a separate post).</p>




<h2>Github Pages</h2>


<p><a href="http://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a> are public web pages for users, organizations, and repositories, that are freely hosted on GitHub’s github.io domain or on a custom domain name of your choice. GitHub Pages are powered by Jekyll behind the scenes, so in addition to supporting regular HTML content, they’re also a great way to host your Jekyll-powered website for free.</p>




<h2>Jekyll</h2>


<p><a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> is a simple, blog-aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory containing raw text files in various formats, runs it through Markdown (or Textile) and Liquid converters, and spits out a complete, ready-to-publish static website suitable for serving with your favorite web server.</p>




<h2>Octopress</h2>


<p><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> is a static blogging framework built on top of Jekyll, which makes it much easier to manage Jekyll-powered websites.</p>




<p>I will cover the details of the Octopress setup, Blogging experience and factors for considering Octopress/Github Pages in separate post(s).</p>


<p></p>

<p>Happy Blogging!</p>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
